Hello everyone, the fourth issue of voice
Всім привіт четвертий випуск голосових
messages and Today I will tell you how
повідомлень і Сьогодні я розповім як
scammers wanted to throw me for money.
мене хотіли кинути шахраї на гроші
In fact, this was the first time in my
насправді це був перший раз в моєму
life that this happened. I have heard many times that
житті таке сталося Я багато разів чув що
this happens when they call just
таке відбувається коли дзвонять просто
on the phone and well, the scammers are trying to
по телефону і ну в шахраї намагаються
find out some bank
там знати якісь банківські реквізити
details there and so on. And they called me too. And
дані там і так далі І мене набрали теж І
I immediately understood that these are scammers. Well, I
я такий відразу зрозумів що це шахраї Ну
think okay, some unknown number, the bank
думаю ладно якийсь невідомий номер банк
never does that. I think I will try to
так ніколи не робить думаю спробую
chat. And that's what came of it.
поспілкуватися І от що з цього вийшло
Now I will just start this recording because
зараз я просто запущу цей запис тому що
as soon as the call started, I
як тільки почався дзвінок Я на телефоні
pressed record on the phone to just
натиснув записати розмову щоб просто
share it with my
потім поділитися насправді там з
parents later so that they don't get into such a story.
батьками щоб вони на таку історію не
But I think it will be interesting to all
потрапили але думаю що буде цікаво всім
subscribers. Let's start with the
підписникам все стартуємо
experience of a scammer. Your conversation
стувальницького досвіду ваша розмова
may be
може бути
recorded by order of the National Bank of
записана за наказом Національного банку
Ukraine
України
in connection with the security policy to
у зв'язку з політикою безпеки для
protect your account from fraudulent
захисту вашого рахунку від шахрайських
actions. Your card has been blocked and
дій ваша картка була заблокована а
the account has been restricted. To
рахунок поставлений під обмеження щоб
pass identification, activate your
пройти ідентифікацію активувати вашу
card and connect to a
карту та підключитися до працівника
bank employee, please.  stay on the
банка будь ласка залишайтесь на
[music]
[музика]
line Good afternoon Good afternoon and you have
лінії Доброго дня Доброго дня а вас
been connected to the security service of the National
з'єдналася служба безпеки національної
Bank of Ukraine
банки України
My name is Svitlana I am listening to you can I
Мене звати Світлана слухаю вас чи мож
help I did not call you it was me You
допомогти я не дзвонив це мені Ви
called I do not know
подзвонили Я не знаю
why I misunderstood you Please tell me
чого я вас зрозуміла Скажіть будь ласка
in the last 15 minutes have you tried to
ви за останні 15 хвилин намагалися
create some transactions with your card in
створити якісь операції вашою карткою в
favor of another bank Mr.
пользу іншого банку пане
Victor I do not have a card at the National Bank And
Віктор в мене нема картки в Нацбанку А
you do not have any other bank besides PrivatBank which bank
ні ви окрім ПриватБанку яким банком
are you using Mr. Victor
обслуговуєтесь пане Вікторе
Well this is confidential information and your
А ну це конфіденційна інформація а вашою
confidential information is the PIN code
конфіденційною інформація - це пін-код
on your card passport personal data the
по вашій карті паспортні анкетні дані
code word that you specified when
кодове слово яке ви вказували при
receiving this card this is your
полученні даної картки ось це Ваша
confidential information and information
конфіденційна інформація та інформація
which bank you use it is
яким банком ви користуєтесь вона
available to second and third parties please
доступна другим та третім особам будь
okay oshchayfaienmban
добре ощайфайенмбан
rsyban Wait I understand something you are from the
рсибан Зачекайте я щось розумію ви з
bank yes from the bank we are bothering you which
банку так з банку вас турбуємо якого
Oschadbank Oschadbank I understood it
Ощадбанк Ощадбанк Я зрозумів
well For what
ее добре По якій
reason that's actually all and what is interesting here first At first
причині от власне і все і що цікаво тут
they said that this
перше Спочатку вони сказали що це
National Bank then when I asked what
Нацбанк потім коли я перепитав що за
bank they said Oschtbank then they
банк сказали ощтбанк потім вони ще До
said before that there was something about Privat Bank Although
цього казали що там про Приват банк Хоча
I didn't say anything about Privat Bank and it's
я про Приватбанк нічого не казав і
clear that when I asked about the
зрозуміло що коли я спитав вже там про
purpose of the call then everything got mixed up but I
ціль дзвінка то все злилось але мені
liked how it was organized yes that is it
сподобалось як воно організовано да
starts with the fact that it seems like a
тобто воно починається з того що ніби
robot is calling and then it seems like I dialed it myself i.e.
дзвонить Робот і потім ніби я сам набрав
they dialed me not I dialed but
тобто вони мене набрали не я набрав але
then I have to wait for the connection with the
потім я маю почекати зв'язку з
operator and it seems like I contacted this
оператором і ніби я зв'язався з цим
operator already of course then it turns out
оператором вже звісно тоді виходить
more trust well that is the hope that I
більше довіри ну тобто сподівання що я
will forget that it was an incoming call and not I myself
забуду що це був вхід дзвінок а не я сам
initiated it let's say so also I
все почав ініціював скажемо так також Я
noticed that I didn't say my name and
помітив що я не називав свого імені і
my name They knew and accordingly it
моє ім'я Вони знали і відповідно це
means that somewhere simply Lately
значить що десь просто Останнім часом
I've been getting a lot of these here some spins
мені дуже оці от якісь спіни дзвонять
some casinos these fathers robots and somewhere in
якісь казино оці отці роботи і десь
short my number most likely just
короче мій номер скоріш за все просто
got into some database and I see that they
попав в якусь базу і я бачу що вони
know my name my number and accordingly they
знають Моє ім'я мій номер і відповідно
call write to  in the comments, have you
оце названюють пишіть в коментарях чи
had such stories in your life, this is a really
були такі історії у вас в житті це прям
cool topic for discussion
класна тема для обговорення